Nancy W. Anderson Papers MS112
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Nancy W. Anderson Papers
1940 -- 1999
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Anderson, Nancy W.
MS112
18.0 Linear Feet 18 boxes; 1 oversize folder
Arrangement
Organized in seven series: Personal; Calendars and appointment books; Subject files; Correspondence; Phone calls; Publications and press; Visual materials.
Scope and Contents
Collection materials include: agendas, appointment books, brochures, correspondence (letters and faxes), itineraries, newspaper and journal clippings, phone call logs, photos, publications, reports, receipts, slides, speech scripts, video.
Functions or activities represented: academic administrative functions, meeting and conference organization (NEEN, EAEN, IUCN), publishing, research, professional networking, and environmental activism.
Significant topics, events, places: local, national, and international environmental organizations; environmental forums and events; environmental legislation; conferences; Africa, Armenia, Australia, Canada, China, India, Massachusetts, Oregon, Russia, Washington.
Biographical / Historical
Nancy W. Anderson (August 7, 1922-November 11, 1997) received a BA in Public Administration from George Washington University in 1944.
Before coming to Tufts, Anderson served as an officer in WAVES (Women Accepted for Volunteer Emergency Service) (1944-46), in part as a Medical Librarian at Bethesda. From 1947 to 1949 she was an Informational Control Officer for the CIA. Her environmental work began in the early 1970s when she volunteered for the Massachusetts Association of Conservation Commissions (MACC) and started editing their newsletter. At that time she also became the Chairman of the Reading Conservation Commission, which looked at water supply and flood plain conservation issues. Because of this work, Anderson Meadow in Reading was named in her honor. She also served as a consultant for the Massachusetts Institute of Governmental Services at the University of Massachusetts at Amherst, helping them to organize environmental evening classes. Beginning in 1975, she acted as coordinator for the Environmental Citizen Advocacy Program, a joint venture of the Lincoln Filene Center and the Tufts program in Environmental Policy.
From 1978 to 1994, Anderson was the Director of Environmental Affairs at the Lincoln Filene Center (LFC). In 1979 she founded the New England Environmental Network (NEEN), an educational network for those concerned about the environment. While at Tufts (1978-1994), she was active in the International Union for the Conservation of Nature (IUCN) and served as the Regional Chairman for their Commission on Education and Communication. In 1989 (or 1990), she co-founded the Eastern Africa Environmental Network to organize environmental educational programs for Africa. Anderson received numerous environmental and citizenship awards and was a sought-after speaker on topics related to the environment and environmental activism. Her publications ranged from newsletters and short articles to handbooks and conference summaries. She also served as an advisor or director for countless environmental organizations, including Grand Circle Travel, Environmental Lobby of Massachusetts, Save the Harbor/Save the Bay, the Coolidge Center for Environmental Leadership, the Water Supply Citizens Advisory Committee, and the Coalition for Environmentally Responsible Economics.
In 1993, Anderson became a Senior Fellow at the LFC, a part-time position. She continued to represent the LFC at the IUCN and served as an honorary Chairman of the EAEN. Her ongoing activism included serving on President Clinton's Council on Sustainable Development.
Anderson retired from the LFC on June 30, 1994. She moved to Maine with her husband but continued her environmental work as a Research Associate for the Global/International Environment and Project Institute at the Tufts Fletcher School of Diplomacy. She also served as a board member for the Senior College at the University of Southern Maine, where she taught courses on Environmental Awareness.
Nancy W. Anderson died on November 11, 1997 at the age of 75. She was survived by Col. John A. Anderson (U.S.M.C. ret.), her husband of 49 years, and two children, Nancy C. Anderson and John A. Anderson, Jr.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Anderson, Nancy W.; New England Environmental Network; Environmentalism; Environmental history
- Personal, 1970 -- 1998; MS112.001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains biographical information. This series brings together various folders found in NWA's subject files originally labeled "NWA personal," "personal," and "profiles." This series contains passports, curriculum vitas, personal profiles, retirement related material, as well as get well cards and condolences sent to NWA's husband upon her death. The folder labeled "Vita and current articles" is one of NWA's original folders and shows how she represented herself.
  Arrangement
  This series is not arranged.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Passports, 1985 -- 1996; MS112.001.001.00001 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Profiles, 1970 -- 1997; MS112.001.001.00002 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Resumes, vitae, job descriptions, synonpses, 1975 -- 1995; MS112.001.001.00003 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Retirement, 1992 -- 1993; MS112.001.001.00004 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Assorted personal, 1975 -- 1994; MS112.001.001.00005 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Inauguration, 1993; MS112.001.001.00006 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Vita and enclosed articles, 1989; MS112.001.001.00007 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
    Nancy W. Anderson profile packet
  - Condolences, remembrances, get well cards, 1997 -- 1998; MS112.001.001.00008 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Recognition and awards, 1978 -- 1993; MS112.001.001.00035 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Photograph dedicated to Nancy Anderson by Stephen Gersh, MS112.001.001.00036 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 6)
    This item is housed in UA136/001-006. This material was found with other unprocessed material and added to the collection, July 2007. No Date Available
- Calendars and appointment books, 1974 -- 1997; MS112.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains bound appointment books for the years between 1974 and 1997, except 1980, 1981, 1983, 1984, 1986, 1988, and 1993. These appointment books usually span the academic calendar, although in some cases they span the calendar year.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Appointment calendars, 1974 -- 1976; MS112.002.001.00009 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Appointment calendars, 1977 -- 1979; MS112.002.001.00010 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Appointment calendars, 1982 -- 1985; MS112.002.001.00011 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Appointment calendars, 1987 -- 1989; MS112.002.001.00012 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Appointment calendar, 1990; MS112.002.001.00013 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Appointment calendar, 1991 -- 1992; MS112.002.001.00014 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Appointment calendar, 1994 -- 1995; MS112.002.001.00015 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
  - Appointment calendar, 1995 -- 1997; MS112.002.001.00016 (Box MS112 Shared 1)
- Subject files, 1968 -- 1999; MS112.003; 13.2 Linear Feet
  This series includes files pertaining to: organizations of which NWA was a member; conferences and events; places and institutions where she gave presentations; professional contacts; environmental concerns. NWA kept more than one alphabetized series for recent and older files. During processing we decided to merge all subject files into one alphabetized series to assist researchers and because the various chronological subject series overlapped extensively. After processing was completed, we discovered that one box of additional subject files had not been accessioned. These files, ranging from 'M' to 'W', were added at the end of the alphabetized run of subject files.
  Subject files generally retain original titles, but dates were added when missing. Titles were added or changed for speeches and some un-filed material. NWA sometimes filed her speeches under "A" for addresses and organized them alphabetically by sponsor. For ease of access, speeches were moved to "S" for "Speeches." In some cases NWA filed her speeches under the sponsoring organization; these speeches remain in the original location. Users are advised to search under "Speeches" and relevant subject files.
  Most un-filed material was filed in their appropriate subject files based on original sticky notes indicating to which file they belonged. In two cases, un-filed material was unlabeled and we created the following subject files: MACC Environmental Education Task Force; Reading Open Land Trust.
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  75 years from the date of creation. Open for research.
  - AAUW (American Association of University Women), 1993; MS112.003.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Africa (1 of 2), 1990 -- 1999; MS112.003.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Africa (2 of 2), 1990; MS112.003.003.00003 (Box 3)
    Date is approximate
  - Agenda 21 - drafts, proceedings (1 of 4), 1993 -- 1994; MS112.003.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Agenda 21 - drafts, proceedings (2 of 4), 1993 -- 1994; MS112.003.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Agenda 21 - drafts, proceedings (3 of 4), 1993 -- 1994; MS112.003.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Agenda 21 - drafts, proceedings (4 of 4), 1993 -- 1994; MS112.003.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Agenda 21 (bound conference proceedings), 1993 -- 1994; MS112.003.003.00008 (Box 3)
    See Phone calls 1993 file, box 14, item 00027
  - Agriculture, 1993; MS112.003.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - American museum of natural sculpture, 1991; MS112.003.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - American River, 1993; MS112.003.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Annual growth management forum, 1990; MS112.003.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Antioch New England Graduate School, 1982; MS112.003.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Armenia, 1989; MS112.003.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Australia, 1990; MS112.003.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Awards, 1973 -- 1993; MS112.003.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - AWIS (Association for Women in Science), 1992; MS112.003.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - Ban clearcutting, 1996; MS112.003.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Bar Association meeting, 1992; MS112.003.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - Beaver Brook Association, 1993; MS112.003.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - Barcy, Brenda - Health effects institute, 1990 -- 1991; MS112.003.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Boston area green pages, 1992 -- 1993; MS112.003.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - Boston center for international visitors, 1993; MS112.003.003.00023 (Box 3)
  - Boston Earth Week, 1992 -- 1993; MS112.003.003.00024 (Box 3)
  - Bowdoin College, 1985 -- 1986; MS112.003.003.00025 (Box 3)
  - Budget, 1990; MS112.003.003.00026 (Box 3)
  - Budget, 1993; MS112.003.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Bunker Hill, Oregon, 1986 -- 1987; MS112.003.003.00028 (Box 3)
  - Caldicott, Helen, 1992; MS112.003.003.00029 (Box 3)
  - Cambridge forum, 1993; MS112.003.003.00030 (Box 3)
  - Canada, 1986 -- 1991; MS112.003.003.00031 (Box 3)
  - Central and East Europe, 1993; MS112.003.003.00032 (Box 3)
  - CERES, 1992 -- 1993; MS112.003.003.00033 (Box 3)
  - Chhetri, Deepak Khatry, 1988 -- 1991; MS112.003.003.00034 (Box 3)
  - China trip (1 of 3), 1985; MS112.003.003.00035 (Box 3)
  - China trip (2 of 3), 1985; MS112.003.003.00036 (Box 3)
  - China trip (3 of 3), 1985; MS112.003.003.00037 (Box 3)
  - Citizen network, 1994; MS112.003.003.00038 (Box 3)
  - Chudyk, Wayne - application for tenure, 1985; MS112.003.003.00039 (Box 3)
    75 years from the date of creation.
    Restricted (faculty tenure application)
  - Clinton, Bill, 1992; MS112.003.003.00040 (Box 3)
  - Clinton, Bill, 1994; MS112.003.003.00041 (Box 3)
  - Coal Fly Ash issue paper, by Richard B. Mahoney, 1981; MS112.003.003.00042 (Box 3)
  - Colby College, 1993; MS112.003.003.00043 (Box 3)
  - Colby Eco Expo, 1993; MS112.003.003.00044 (Box 3)
  - Coolidge center, 1983; MS112.003.003.00045 (Box 3)
  - Council on economic priorities, 1993; MS112.003.003.00046 (Box 3)
  - Current conferences, 1993 -- 1994; MS112.003.003.00047 (Box 3)
  - Dean of Environmental Studies, 1993; MS112.003.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Directories, 1994 -- 1995; MS112.003.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Dow Chemical - Dale Humbert (1 of 2), 1989 -- 1992; MS112.003.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Dow Chemical - Dale Humbert (2 of 2), 1989 -- 1992; MS112.003.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - EAEN, 1988 -- 1990; MS112.003.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - EAEN, 1990; MS112.003.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Agenda for orginizational meeting, 1990; MS112.003.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Conference (brochures, publications), 1990; MS112.003.004.00008 (Box 4)
    September
  - EAEN Proposal, 1990 -- 1992; MS112.003.004.00009 (Box 4)
    Includes Agenda 21 proposal, 1992
  - EAEN (1 of 2), 1991; MS112.003.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - EAEN (2 of 2), 1991; MS112.003.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Africa Nairobi trip, 1991; MS112.003.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Africa, 1991; MS112.003.004.00013 (Box 4)
    June
  - EAEN Africa travel, 1991; MS112.003.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Africa, 1991; MS112.003.004.00015 (Box 4)
    Includes EAEN directory, budget, June
  - EAEN conference information from summer newsletter, 1991; MS112.003.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Chumo, Nathaniel (1 of 4), 1991; MS112.003.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Chumo, Nathaniel (2 of 4), 1991; MS112.003.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Chumo, Nathaniel (3 of 4), 1991; MS112.003.004.00019 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Chumo, Nathaniel (4 of 4), 1991; MS112.003.004.00020 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Randrianasolo, Voare and Bodo, 1991; MS112.003.004.00021 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Network (1 of 2), 1991 -- 1992; MS112.003.004.00022 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Network (2 of 2), 1991 -- 1992; MS112.003.004.00023 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Newsletters, 1991 -- 1992; MS112.003.004.00024 (Box 4)
  - EAEN plan, 1991 -- 1992; MS112.003.004.00025 (Box 4)
  - EAEN (1 of 2), 1992; MS112.003.004.00026 (Box 4)
  - EAEN (2 of 2), 1992; MS112.003.004.00027 (Box 4)
  - EAEN Africa, 1992; MS112.003.004.00028 (Box 4)
  - EAEN unfiled material, 1992; MS112.003.004.00029 (Box 4)
  - EAEN, 1993; MS112.003.004.00030 (Box 4)
  - EAEN (1 of 2), 1994; MS112.003.004.00031 (Box 4)
  - EAEN (2 of 2), 1994; MS112.003.004.00032 (Box 4)
  - EAEN proceedings, 1994; MS112.003.004.00033 (Box 4)
  - EAEN newsletters, 1994; MS112.003.004.00034 (Box 4)
  - EAEN, 1996; MS112.003.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - EAEN Nairobi Africa meeting, 1996; MS112.003.005.00002 (Box 5)
    May
  - EAEN program, 1997; MS112.003.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Earth Day, 1994; MS112.003.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Earth Day forum, 1995; MS112.003.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Earth summit, 1993; MS112.003.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - Eastern Massachusetts sustainable development network, 1992; MS112.003.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - Eco Expo, 1993; MS112.003.005.00008 (Box 5)
  - Eco Expo (Nancy Anderson material), 1993; MS112.003.005.00009 (Box 5)
    Anderson, Nancy W.
  - Economics of open space, 1971 -- 1975; MS112.003.005.00010 (Box 5)
  - Education, 1995; MS112.003.005.00011 (Box 5)
  - Education subcommittee on environmental research education and policy, 1987; MS112.003.005.00012 (Box 5)
  - Environment and energy study institute, 1986; MS112.003.005.00013 (Box 5)
  - Ells, Stephen, 1993; MS112.003.005.00014 (Box 5)
    Ells: a public service fellow nominee
  - ELTI (Environmental Leadership Training Institute) (1 of 2), 1993; MS112.003.005.00015 (Box 5)
  - ELTI (2 of 2), 1993; MS112.003.005.00016 (Box 5)
  - ELTI evaluations (1 of 2), 1993; MS112.003.005.00017 (Box 5)
    Restricted (course evaluations)
  - ELTI evaluations (2 of 2), 1993; MS112.003.005.00018 (Box 5)
  - Environmental business council, 1994; MS112.003.005.00019 (Box 5)
  - Environmental diversity forum (1 of 2), 1991 -- 1993; MS112.003.005.00020 (Box 5)
  - Environmental diversity forum (2 of 2), 1991 -- 1993; MS112.003.005.00021 (Box 5)
  - Environmental economics, 1978; MS112.003.005.00022 (Box 5)
  - Environmental education act, 1974; MS112.003.005.00023 (Box 5)
  - Environmental futures, 1994; MS112.003.005.00024 (Box 5)
  - Environmental League of Massachusetts, 1994; MS112.003.005.00025 (Box 5)
  - Environmental League of Massachusetts selection committee, 1993; MS112.003.005.00026 (Box 5)
    January 8
  - Environmental science and politics book, 1990; MS112.003.005.00027 (Box 5)
  - Environmental studies committee, 1983 -- 1986; MS112.003.005.00028 (Box 5)
  - EPA, 1993; MS112.003.005.00029 (Box 5)
  - EPA, 1996; MS112.003.005.00030 (Box 5)
  - Expenses (un-filed requests), 1993; MS112.003.005.00031 (Box 5)
  - Faxes to Clinton, 1993; MS112.003.005.00032 (Box 5)
  - Floodplain/Wetland, 1974 -- 1983; MS112.003.005.00033 (Box 5)
  - Floodplain zoning, 1972 -- 1983; MS112.003.005.00034 (Box 5)
  - Florin, Alexendru, 1993; MS112.003.005.00035 (Box 5)
  - Forestry (1 of 3), 1989 -- 1994; MS112.003.005.00036 (Box 5)
    Includes clearcutting photos
  - Forestry (2 of 3), 1989 -- 1994; MS112.003.005.00037 (Box 5)
  - Forestry (3 of 3), 1989 -- 1994; MS112.003.005.00038 (Box 5)
  - Forestry at Rio, 1992; MS112.003.005.00039 (Box 5)
  - Fort Devens, 1992; MS112.003.005.00040 (Box 5)
  - Forum (Acheiving sustainable development in New England) (1 of 2), 1995; MS112.003.006.00001 (Box 6)
    March 17
  - Forum (Acheiving sustainable development in New England) (2 of 2), 1995; MS112.003.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - Foster proposal, 1984; MS112.003.006.00003 (Box 6)
    August
  - Framingham papers, 1974; MS112.003.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - Framingham State College final report, 1974; MS112.003.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Friends of the Earth, 1994; MS112.003.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - Friends of the Earth - Blackwelder, Brent, 1996; MS112.003.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - GAIN, 1993; MS112.003.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - GDAE, 1995; MS112.003.006.00009 (Box 6)
  - Georges Bank, 1979 -- 1983; MS112.003.006.00010 (Box 6)
  - Gersh, Stephan, 1991 -- 1992; MS112.003.006.00011 (Box 6)
  - Geesteranus, Chris Maas, 1990 -- 1991; MS112.003.006.00012 (Box 6)
  - Global environment facility, 1993; MS112.003.006.00013 (Box 6)
  - Global Tomorrow Coalition, 1994; MS112.003.006.00014 (Box 6)
  - Governer's conference, 1993; MS112.003.006.00015 (Box 6)
    May 25-28
  - Grand Circle Travel (1 of 2), 1992 -- 1994; MS112.003.006.00016 (Box 6)
  - Grand Circle Travel (2 of 2), 1992 -- 1994; MS112.003.006.00017 (Box 6)
  - Grand Circle Travel, 1994 -- 1996; MS112.003.006.00018 (Box 6)
  - Grand Circle Travel (brochures), 1994; MS112.003.006.00019 (Box 6)
  - Greenfield, 1975; MS112.003.006.00020 (Box 6)
  - Guide to floodplain zoning, 1974; MS112.003.006.00021 (Box 6)
  - Hargreaves, John, 1992; MS112.003.006.00022 (Box 6)
  - Hargreaves, John, 1993; MS112.003.006.00023 (Box 6)
  - Hazardous waste, 1994; MS112.003.006.00024 (Box 6)
  - Hilton honors, 1996 -- 1997; MS112.003.006.00025 (Box 6)
  - Holdgate, Martin, 1989 -- 1991; MS112.003.006.00026 (Box 6)
  - Hormel, Chris (1 of 2), 1990 -- 1994; MS112.003.006.00027 (Box 6)
  - Hormel, Chris (2 of 2), 1990 -- 1994; MS112.003.006.00028 (Box 6)
  - HUD insurance program, 1973 -- 1974; MS112.003.006.00029 (Box 6)
  - Hydro Quebec, 1993; MS112.003.006.00030 (Box 6)
  - Hydro Quebec, 1994; MS112.003.006.00031 (Box 6)
  - IERS, 1992; MS112.003.006.00032 (Box 6)
  - India, 1990; MS112.003.006.00033 (Box 6)
  - India international conference, 1990; MS112.003.006.00034 (Box 6)
  - Inroads, 1993; MS112.003.006.00035 (Box 6)
  - IPA program, 1974; MS112.003.006.00036 (Box 6)
  - Ipswich River watershed district program, 1969 -- 1975; MS112.003.006.00037 (Box 6)
  - Ipswich River studies (1 of 2), 1972 -- 1973; MS112.003.006.00038 (Box 6)
  - Ipswich River studies (2 of 2), 1972 -- 1973; MS112.003.006.00039 (Box 6)
  - IUCN un-filed notebook, MS112.003.007.00001 (Box 7)
    No Date Available
  - IUCN, 1983 -- 1990; MS112.003.007.00002 (Box 7)
    Includes photos 1990
  - IUCN Africa trip, education, 1988 -- 1990; MS112.003.007.00003 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Perth, press releases, 1990; MS112.003.007.00004 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Resolutions, Australia, 1990; MS112.003.007.00005 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Resolutions and recommendations, 1990; MS112.003.007.00006 (Box 7)
    Includes other IUCN publications
  - IUCN Australia travel arrangements, 1990; MS112.003.007.00007 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Australia (1 of 2), 1990 -- 1991; MS112.003.007.00008 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Australia (2 of 2), 1990 -- 1991; MS112.003.007.00009 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Current (1 of 3), 1990 -- 1991; MS112.003.007.00010 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Current (2 of 3), 1990 -- 1991; MS112.003.007.00011 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Current (3 of 3), 1990 -- 1991; MS112.003.007.00012 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Africa June (1 of 2), 1991; MS112.003.007.00013 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Africa June (2 of 2), 1991; MS112.003.007.00014 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Education and communication meeting, NEEC, 1991; MS112.003.007.00015 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Steering committee, 1991; MS112.003.007.00016 (Box 7)
    December 2-4. Includes committee on education and communication 1992
  - IUCN Membership directory, 1992; MS112.003.007.00017 (Box 7)
    Includes other IUCN material
  - IUCN Commission on education and training, 1991 -- 1992; MS112.003.007.00018 (Box 7)
  - IUCN North American regional committe on education and training (1 of 2), 1992; MS112.003.007.00019 (Box 7)
  - IUCN North American regional committe on education and training (2 of 2), 1992; MS112.003.007.00020 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Commission on education and training, 1993; MS112.003.007.00021 (Box 7)
  - IUCN Earth Times, 1993; MS112.003.007.00022 (Box 7)
  - IUCN U.S. task force (1 of 2), 1994; MS112.003.007.00023 (Box 7)
  - IUCN U.S. task force (2 of 2), 1994; MS112.003.007.00024 (Box 7)
  - IUCN, 1993 -- 1994; MS112.003.007.00025 (Box 7)
  - IUCN 1 (1 of 2), 1993 -- 1994; MS112.003.007.00026 (Box 7)
  - IUCN 1 (2 of 2), 1993 -- 1994; MS112.003.007.00027 (Box 7)
  - IUCN 2 (1 of 2), 1993 -- 1994; MS112.003.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - IUCN 2 (2 of 2), 1993 -- 1994; MS112.003.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - IUCN un-filed publications, 1993 -- 1994; MS112.003.008.00003 (Box 8)
    Includes EAEN 1995
  - IUCN North American region, 1993; MS112.003.008.00004 (Box 8)
  - IUCN 3, 1994; MS112.003.008.00005 (Box 8)
  - IUCN, 1995; MS112.003.008.00006 (Box 8)
    Includes 1998 obituary material and NEEN material
  - IUCN Montreal (1 of 2), 1996; MS112.003.008.00007 (Box 8)
  - IUCN Montreal (2 of 2), 1996; MS112.003.008.00008 (Box 8)
  - IUCN unlabeled file (1 of 2), 1995 -- 1996; MS112.003.008.00009 (Box 8)
  - IUCN unlabeled file (2 of 2), 1995 -- 1996; MS112.003.008.00010 (Box 8)
  - IUCN unlabeled file, 1996; MS112.003.008.00011 (Box 8)
  - IUCN Burke, John, 1990 -- 1991; MS112.003.008.00012 (Box 8)
  - IUCN McNeeley, Jeffrey, 1991; MS112.003.008.00013 (Box 8)
  - IUCN Munro, Dr. David, 1992; MS112.003.008.00014 (Box 8)
  - IUCN Pilgrim, Hugh, 1991; MS112.003.008.00015 (Box 8)
  - IUCN Rotich, Nehemia arap, 1991; MS112.003.008.00016 (Box 8)
  - IUCN Sarathy, Partha, 1990 -- 1993; MS112.003.008.00017 (Box 8)
    Includes "Brama" by Partha Sarathy
  - IUCN Smyth, John, 1989; MS112.003.008.00018 (Box 8)
  - IUCN Swift, Byron, 1991 -- 1992; MS112.003.008.00019 (Box 8)
  - IUCN "Secrets of volunteer success", 1989; MS112.003.008.00020 (Box 8)
    Lincoln Filene Center publiction filed with IUCN material
  - IUCN "Networks-how to build an environmental network", 1991; MS112.003.008.00021 (Box 8)
    Includes IUCN education commission material
  - James Bay, 1989 -- 1994; MS112.003.008.00022 (Box 8)
  - James Bay Hydro Electric Power Quebec, 1991 -- 1992; MS112.003.008.00023 (Box 8)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1992; MS112.003.008.00024 (Box 8)
  - Kudos, etc., 1990 -- 1992; MS112.003.008.00025 (Box 8)
  - League of Conservation Voters, report, 1996; MS112.003.008.00026 (Box 8)
  - Lego World, 1992; MS112.003.008.00027 (Box 8)
  - Light Hawk, 1989; MS112.003.008.00028 (Box 8)
  - Lincoln Filene Center, 1990 -- 1992; MS112.003.008.00029 (Box 8)
  - Lincoln Filene Center, monthly reports, 1990 -- 1993; MS112.003.008.00030 (Box 8)